Patrick McGuigan

Software Engineer

339-788-1008 // Denver, Colorado

patrick.mcguigan5@gmail.com// https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickmcguigan// https://pmsoftware.netlify.app// https://github.com/pattshreds//

I am a Software Engineer with experience building projects using **Javascript**, **React.JS**, **PostgreSQL**, **MongoDB** and **Node.JS** as well as other programming languages and technologies. While I am passionate about technology, development, and design, I also find joy in gaining new or deepening my current knowledge; technology and beyond.

PROJECTS

PokéSearch // GitHub

PokéSearch is a frontend application built in **HTML**, **CSS**, **Javascript** and **jQuery** using a third party API for the data. This project displays my ability to optimize until everything works and is built in an efficient way.

Moodset // GitHub

Moodset is a full stack application built with **Javascript**, **Node.JS**, **Mongoose**, **Express.JS** and **.EJS** using an **MVC** design pattern. One of the main challenges I encountered was getting MP3 files to upload and play. My analytical skills helped me research and build until solving this problem using tools such as **Bcrypt**, **Cloudinary**, **Mongoose**, **Multer** and others.

Infinite Savannah // GitHub

Infinite Savannah is a full stack application built with the **MERN stack** (MongoDB, Express.JS, React, Node.JS). This application was a team effort which relied on the **Agile** methodology and **Trello** to manage progress.

Rezu // GitHub

Rezu is a full stack application built with the **PERN stack** (PostgreSQL, Express.JS, React, Node.JS) in which I displayed strategic planning by designing and organizing the back-end before creating the React App.

EXPERIENCE

Production Specialist // Friction Labs // 2021 -

- Use my production expertise to modify and improve our workflow by designing methods for each step in the process.
- Maintain and repair production machinery to ensure efficiency and a high quality product.

Software Engineer // Hack for LA // 2021 - 2022

- Volunteered with the HFLA website team using Git to fix front-end and back-end issues via pull requests.
- Attended weekly meetings to discuss current and potential future issues on the HFLA website.

Sales Advisor // PMG - Porsche // 2018 - 2020

- Developed long lasting relationships with clients through strong and consistent communication.
- Worked as a team with all departments to ensure an all around smooth customer experience.
- Executed professional sales streams that lead to efficiency and organization by utilizing good CRM software.

Supervisor, Route Setter, Instructor // Rock Spot Climbing // 2012 - 2018

- Oversaw all gym operations and delegated important tasks to employees.
- Prepared itineraries for our B-level climbing team, and assisted in leading team practice.
- Designed and tested intuitive and high quality indoor rock climbing routes.

EDUCATION

Immersive Bootcamp Certificate // Software Engineering // General Assembly // Remote

Bachelor of Arts // Major in graphic design | Minor in Fine Arts // Curry College // Boston, Massachusetts